In today's video, you're going to learn how to create cinematic sequences with Seedarts 2.5, and that starts with understanding where you can find the
highest quality references for you to get good ideas from.
It also includes the script writing process, how you can use Claude to elevate your work and not replace what you do.
It's designing detailed character sheets, it's creating the perfect location reference for your project.
It's also learning the physical process of doing C Dance 2.5 generations, as well as getting consistent voices across all your generations.
We'll even touch a little bit on the post-production process from editing all the way to sound design.
I am not going to edit this video for YouTube retention purposes.
Every tutorial out there that exists right now actually skips so much important context and also problem solving.
So I'm going to keep every single thing that I get wrong inside this video so that I can show you the remedy. Because you will run into problems when you try to create high-quality work with AI.
It is a natural part of it. But the hardest part is learning how to overcome those problems.
By the end of this video, you will leave with all of the skills that you need to be able to charge between five to fifty thousand dollars
for your AI projects. So without further ado, let's get started. The first thing we need to do is go to this website right here.
Now, this website is called Shop Deck, and this is where you can find the highest quality references and also a just fantastic place for you to start with ideation.
So, what is ShopDeck?
It's a platform that has a bunch of frames from movies, commercials, and they're all really, really pretty.
And they've got such good color grading on them too.
So, if for example, you're stuck with how do I get a good color grade for my project?
Well, you can find specific frames and they also have all the hex codes broken down for each of the projects.
So you can go in here and look at all of the rich data of this frame.
Check this out here.
They've also got the uh the actual filming location, they've got the camera that was used in here, and if we go on some of these other frames here,
you can even see the lenses that they use to create specific results.
Now, why is this important?
Well, it's because all of this data is data that we can then give to Claude to help us replicate similar results for our own projects.
So if there is a specific look and style that you want to achieve, you can use this website to really lock in that style across all of your video generations
for the entire project.
This is a huge step that people miss.
People seem to think that they can design an image and then generate those videos, and each frame that they create in the video generator is going to look the same.
Well, if it's not shot on the same camera or you don't instruct it to do so, it's going to feel different between each of the frames.
So the reason why continuity feels great between Netflix shots is because they're using the same gear for each of the shots,
so it feels natural and consistent.
You're not getting that focal change or aperture change, you're getting the consistent depth of field, everything remains consistent, and that's what you need with your video generations as well.
And this platform gives you that data in order to do so.
So that's why I love this platform.
So, how would we actually use Shot Deck in our workflow?
Well, Shot Deck is really used to help you find a vibe and an emotion that you want to portray in your cinematic project.
So if the tone of your video is going to be comedic, or if it's going to be funny, if it's going to be serious, you might find a specific lighting or color
grade to match that scene.
Especially if you've got something visioned in your head already.
Maybe it's going to be a cinematic project like this.
You can lock in this color grade from the get-go, as well as all of this information here.
You can see even the film stocks in here, lenses, the camera body, everything, the lighting, everything you can kind of replicate.
So this is a really, really great place to just get rich data so that you can make amazing imagery.
So let's say you'd found an image that you wanted to create and make your own version of it for your scene.
Well, how would you go about doing that?
Well, this is exactly what I did.
So I found this video on social media, right? And I was like, I love this opening scene here.
What I also love about this in particular is just this opening frame is so captivating to me.
It was so like interesting, and just in a sea of videos, when you're scrolling on your phone and trying to get the viewers' attention,
you need to have, first of all, great lighting, great composition, and good framing, right? So all of these things are really, really important.
And what you can do on Shop Deck as well is when you're scrolling through Shop Deck, imagine this feed of images is like social media videos.
And think to yourself, what grabs my attention?
What cuts through the noise?
Because when you are scrolling through here and I see this, I see this that cuts through the noise in all of these frames here.
Why?
The lighting.
The lighting is so crisp, the colors, everything here is really vibrant, and it just catches my attention in a sea of images.
So this is already a good starting indication that the idea, the lighting, the composition, all of these things are going to capture the viewer's attention when they look at it on their phone screen.
So use this as a dummy feed to help you find images, compositions, lighting that cut through the noise.
Same way, when I look at all of these images right here, this image here captivates my attention.
Me personally.
It sparks curiosity. Is it fear? What is the emotion this character is feeling here in this scene?
It grabs my attention.
Everything else doesn't like, it doesn't leave me this open-ended feedback where I'm like, I look at this scene and I think, yeah, that's pretty,
but it's not like it's not begging me to watch or want to learn more.
This, however, is.
Also, this is definitely like begging me to learn what is this scene about? The visuals here are really pretty.
What is this crazy, like weird environment?
I want to learn more.
So anything that grabs my attention like that, sparks curiosity, is a great place to start for you to use a frame that you can then riff
off to then use in social media because it is going to capture the viewer's attention.
And that's what everything is about.
So, as I said, I found this video right here.
Now, this page I'd recommend all of you go and follow if you're looking to create good quality AI work.
Now, this guy here has an incredible library of cinematic AI visuals, and they're all beautiful environments that you can be inspired by to start your own projects.
All of these are great location references.
Consider it like a Pinterest board of just beautiful scenes that you can use as inspiration. Like these are beautiful locations that you could start your projects in.
So I would really use these as inspiration, and all of them are made on mid-journey.
So, how would we take something like this and create our own version in Midjourney?
Well, I'm glad you asked.
So the first thing we do is find the video or the frame that we want to make our own version.
So what you could do is either just take a screenshot of this frame, like so, and we could then go to mid-journey.
Now, I would recommend that all of you get a mid-journey account, and what we can do is just upload it into our prompt bar in Mid Journey.
Or you can click on this little icon in here and click upload.
So you can just simply upload your saved image inside the prompt bar. Now you'll see it'll be saved in your preset images in here.
And what we can do is you want to upload it in the style reference section in here, and you want to upload it in the image prompt section in here.
And we'll run through why in just a second.
Now the next thing we want to do is go into Claude, okay?
And let's start a brand new chat here in Claude and let's upload our image frame inside Claude as well.
And say, I love this cinematic style, I love the lighting, I love the composition, I love a lot about this image.
Can you write me a mid-journey prompt that will help me recreate this image in the same style, lens, everything?
And what's interesting about this is that if I've taken this frame from a social media video, but what's great about using shot deck is you can actually take, for example,
let's say it was this image here.
You could take a screenshot of just this, all of this data like this, screenshot, boom, and you could then bring that into Claude, right?
Upload it in here.
Let's just say we did this, for example.
Then it has all of that data with all of this information down here.
So when it goes to write the prompt and it's thinking in mid-journey language, it's gonna use the same camera body, camera lens, everything that it needs to replicate a similar color and tone.
So for example, if I save this image and we just did it with this one right here, we can go back into mid-journey, upload this image that we've just saved, put it right into mid-journey in here.
Now I'm gonna clear out all of my references and I'm gonna upload this image inside my style references and image prompts.
Now we can go back into our Claude here and we can copy our prompt, right? So here is our prompt, and let's see.
You can see here inside our prompt, it's even got the Aria Alexa 35, and it's also got the signature prime wide lens.
And if I go back and cross-reference, we've got the Aria Alexa 35 and the signature prime lens.
So you can see it's taken that information.
Now, inside Midjourney, we can simply paste that in like so.
Now it's going to go and create a similar shot with a similar vibe and similar color grade and everything to our original scene.
Now, let me show you. If you click on your prompts, by the way, it will load it back into your prompt bar in Midjourney.
Now, in here, if we click on add images, you can see that we've not only got image prompts, style references, but we've also got attached to prompt.
If I put an image in here and I run it, you'll see what will happen.
It will create that exact scene, the exact same.
And I'll show you why you might want to do that.
We'll let that load in right here.
So here is our own mid-journey inspired versions, and you can see those kind of coming through right here.
And now here is the kind of like similar to the original. So you can see here it's created some which are sticking much more to the original adherence of the original shot.
Now, this is super interesting because what you could do is you could then download this image and you could go into the edit section in mid-journey,
okay, and we can click on edit new image, upload image, and we can upload our frame that we've just created from mid-journey in here.
And you'll see it all loaded in.
Now we can go ahead and remove the characters, and we can also add in some foreground elements.
For example, let's say we wanted to add in like a bush or something in the foreground of this scene.
We can go ahead and just remove everything that we want to remove inside the scene.
So let's just say water in the middle and add a bush in the foreground is blurred out
on the right side.
Okay?
So we're editing just by describing what we want.
And Midjourney is incredible for this.
Why?
And it's much better than Photoshop.
That's because Photoshop has a very limited data set of images that it can use for its generative film model.
Whereas Midjourney has so much more rich context and data that it can use to pull from to create better imagery.
So now we've got four options, and you can see some of them will be pretty messed up, but got two options in here, these two right here, that are pretty good.
And I'd say this one is pretty spot on.
We might then want to download our image, bring it into Photoshop, and then edit small parts like this, for example, just to like fix up anything that we want.
And you could then use this as a location reference if you wanted to.
But if you wanted to create something more unique, more your own, more different, then you could also go down the mid-journey route and let it create its own version of the image
instead of using it as a specific reference to kind of lock in the entire same composition.
So let's say for this project where we're in the park and we've got this lovely bench, how could we go about doing the same?
So let's do it right together right now.
So what we're going to do is we're going to upload under the image prompt section our reference of the image as well as the style reference.
And then we're going to go into Claude and I'm going to copy our prompt here.
Let's go back and start a new chat.
So let's upload our image frame of our screenshot, which is right here.
And let's say let's try to keep it as consistent to the original as possible.
All right.
Maybe we could also add, because I can see that Midjourney is creating almost this like this shot here looks much more photorealistic, I'd say,
than this shot here. This shot here looks like very plasticky and grainy.
So what we can also do is I'm actually gonna turn on my personalization.
And personalization just means when you sign up to Midjourney, you click left or right on an image to say whether or not you like the left image or the right image.
And when you do that, it's training your own personalization key to identify what kind of images you like.
And I like really nice, crisp, photo-realistic portrait style imagery.
So I'm going to turn on my personalization to try and guide it a little bit more to help us get more results that feel more original to the style that I'm looking for.
So now we've got our prompt from Claude.
Let's go back in here and let's paste that in.
So while that's loading, I'm also going to try a version, which is let's upload it under the attach to prompt section.
So I'm going to upload it in this section, upload a style reference as well, and let's prompt that too. So we've got two versions loading in right here.
Now, while that's also loading, let's try. I mean, it's so fast.
I mean, look at that.
So here we have the one that's very similar to the original, but now we've got some like more volumetric lighting coming in here. We've got a couple of like subtle variations.
Now, on top of that, we've got some of our own custom versions in here, which is like very far away.
If it's like too far away, for example, we can just go back into Claude and we can say, right now, our image is too far away.
I'm gonna show you an example, and I'd like you to edit it so it's much closer to the original image that I provided you.
So now we're going back with Claude and we're using it to iterate.
We're using it to guide us to get closer to that result that we want. Locking in these location references is super, super important in the early stages of your project.
Getting the right color grade, getting the right location reference probably takes the longest thing out of anything that you're gonna do in the AI project.
So we can now go back and forth with mid-journey until we have something that we're totally happy with.
So I'm gonna click on both of these, load it back into our prompt, and run it again.
So now let's see if we get any differing results.
So hopefully we'll be a little bit closer to the bench now.
Now, what you can also do here is a mid-journey tip for you. You can load these back into your prompt bar.
Let's go into the settings, and you can increase the weirdness.
Now, what does weirdness do or even variety? Let's just do a little bit of both.
Okay, so what this does is it means that each of the four images that we get, so one, two, three, four, are going to be looking different.
They're going to have more variety between them.
So now that we've upped the variety, hopefully you'll see a more significant difference between each of these four shots.
We have a look at these.
This is a nice shot.
This is not so bad.
This one's pretty good, I'd say.
And this one's also very good.
So you can see here we're now designing some more of our own location references in here.
And we've got a lot more variety between these four shots coming in. And you can see we've got some of those. That's a good one.
This is a really nice one.
That's also pretty good too.
So there's some really nice location references in here.
And we can also take some of these images, we can upscale them, make them look crisp, high res if you wanted to.
The opportunity is there if you wish to do so.
So that's how you can start creating some of your own references based on existing references that you kind of like the look of for your location.
One thing that I also recommend that you do is that you take screenshots of certain color grades and references that you also like, because you can then upload them into
any mood boarding tool.
I'm using a platform called MilaNote to do this, and you can just take references of things that you enjoy.
Now, what's really, really cool about Shot Deck as well is you might find a color grade of a certain scene that you like.
So let's say it's this image here.
Now you'll see underneath it, it will also show you similar images that have a similar composition or maybe even a similar lighting structure.
So you can kind of go through and find specific references that you enjoy.
Now you can start bringing some of those into a mood boarding project because it's going to really impact and be really helpful later on when it comes to writing the Seedance
2.5 video prompts.
So we'll come on to that a little bit later.
But I would recommend making sure that you have a screenshot reference library of all of these images and also this data under here
if that's the kind of video style that you want for your video.
That'll come in later on in the video.
So now it's time to start writing your scripts.
Now, script writing is probably one of the hardest parts for most people.
That's because you have to picture an idea in your head and you have to actually have an idea.
Now, if you're struggling to come up with ideas, you can use platforms like ShotDeck to help you come up with random concepts that you want to make videos on.
Or the other thing that I like to do when it comes to coming up with ideas is listen to music.
That really gets me inspired, but whatever creative medium it is that helps you come up with ideas, whether that's watching movies or listening to music,
both of those things really help me come up with great ideas.
I also love watching Instagram reels, that really helps me come up with creative concepts as well. There's some great cinematographers on Instagram.
So that's also where I like to get a lot of good references from.
Script writing for me is the least sexy process of this entire thing.
But it's the part that most people will fall flat on and most people will fail on.
And this is what makes or breaks your project.
So I cannot express the importance of this, even though it's going to be the least sexy part of the video.
So please bear with me. I'm going to give you all the golden nuggets that I've got.
So this is what script writing to me looks like.
It is me putting my ideas on paper, you know, digital paper anyway. You can basically see my thought processes inside my head.
And I'm literally writing as though I'm directing on set.
So I'm gonna let's punch in here so we can see closer.
So it's me saying it starts with a wide shot of me and my friend sitting on a bench, and we can see it from an aerial
down looking at me sitting on the bench from the same angle as the reference image.
And for that, I know inside Claude, I'm gonna be giving Claude a reference image that looks like this.
So I'm gonna be uploading my location reference in here, and I'm saying that I want me and my friend sat on the bench from the same angle as the reference image that I've provided.
So I'm directing it.
So the camera holds on this scene for two seconds, and we can hear the park ambience and subtle bird sounds.
So we're directing the audio as well.
You have to think about lots of different things when you're directing C dance 2.5.
You have to think about the camera angle.
Where is the camera positioned in the scene?
Okay?
So the first two seconds, I'm thinking my camera is aerial looking down.
I'm thinking about where the camera's positioned, I'm thinking about where the characters are positioned.
So I've instructed that they are sat on the bench.
Also instructing how long is this sequence or part of the sequence going to be?
And I've said it's gonna be two seconds long.
So we've got two seconds, me sat on the bench, and we've got the audio that we can hear in the scene.
And you need to be thinking about all these things in parallel when you are directing CDance 2.5.
So then I say it cuts to a shot of me watching my phone, and I'm reacting to Instagram Reel about AI agents and how they can do my whole job for me, and there's no need to do any more work ever again.
Okay?
So just so you are aware of roughly what that looks like, here is a rough first generation of what that looks like.
AI agents can do his entire job now, nobody needs to work.
Okay, so everything that I've just described pretty much made that scene.
Now, it's not perfect, but we're gonna come on to this a little bit later.
So then I say I get visibly upset and frustrated.
The most important thing, and the biggest tip that I can give you about this script writing process is you have to understand acting
nuances and performance.
The human emotion that comes from the acting delivery is key.
And if you have good emotional intelligence, you will also be so, so good.
It's such transferable skill because it is you looking at real people and understanding how they feel in certain settings and environments.
And you are now directing that.
So, if you have a high emotional intelligence and you can read people, and you can understand how someone is feeling in a certain situation,
just from the acting performance of their nuances that they're delivering live, when they —maybe, they receive a sad piece of news —and.
you see the eyebrow performance, and you see the lines on the forehead come. and you can see the head tilt, and you picture all of these things. and perhaps you think about the eyes.
What is the eye performance?
What is there a quiver on the lip?
All of these nuances that you see. Maybe their shoulders drop in disappointment.
Think of all of these subtle things that that make acting performances so great.
You have to be able to describe these things.
So English writing is actually so, so important.
So here I say I get visibly upset and frustrated.
I throw my phone at the floor and I make a frustrated noise as I throw it at the grass.
The reason being is because I want to throw it at the floor, and if I don't tell it that it's landing on the grass, it's gonna make a sound like it's landing on a piece of concrete.
So you need to direct what is happening, what is the phone landing on.
Now that I've said it's the grass, now when the phone hits the gr it hits the grass, it's gonna make that thud noise that it would if it I actually threw my phone on the floor.
Okay?
You hear the thud of my orange iPhone 17 Pro Max hitting the floor, and I say in a frustrated tone.
So verbal descriptions of how the the voice performance is being delivered is key. It is so important.
So I say, frustrated face, what's the effing point, right? What is the effing point?
And that is like I say that and I'm picturing it in my head.
Okay, my friend is Australian who sits next to me.
So I'm giving that person an accent.
I'm I'm making them a real person.
I'm not just saying my friend is sat next to me, I'm saying my friend from Southeast Asia who has a twang of an accent from X
and X.
Or I'm saying my friend from Austin, Texas is sat next to me. So I'm allocating a voice, I'm allocating a nuance to that character so that we can actually deliver that in a very specific way.
And then whenever we do that scene, we're always going to tell Seedance that that character is Australian and we're going to
describe specifically where that individual's from so it can allocate that voice to that character and it will help us get a consistent voice.
So I say, My friend is Australian who sits next to me while he's playing with a Tamagotchi.
He looks quickly as though I'm overreacting, and he's kind of chuckling and holding back a smile, and he says, Of what?
Right? So I thought about all the acting performance, and this is that scene right here.
What's the fucking point?
Of what?
Right?
So all of that description comes into a very, very small two second segment.
But you have to be that detailed.
You have to be focused on all the nuances in order to get the highest level of acting performance and energy that you get inside your videos.
So all of these things are key.
With the script writing process, I then write out and I do this for the entire script.
So I'll think of a story. What I like to do is I like to think of a story.
So what is the message that I'm trying to deliver from this project?
Well, for me, this project was about how AI agents, I hate them in the creative process.
I don't think that they belong there because I believe there should be a struggle and I like being challenged as a creative.
I don't want the creation process to be easy, and having the cheat codes does not make life fun.
So that was what the project was about for me.
And I wanted to convey that message through something, but I didn't know what.
So I decided to convey this message through a Tamagotchi.
I thought of an object that lots of people know about, maybe had growing up, or maybe had bought for their children, for example.
And I then used that as a way to tell the story.
So I actually narrated the entire story through the Tamagotchi.
So let's watch the project in its full entirety right now, and then we can go and have a look at the rest of the project and how this was all tied together,
made in Seedance, etc.
Agents can do your entire job. I don't even need to work anymore. What's the fucking point?
Of what?
AI agents! Like, why the fuck are we even building them? They do your job for you, bro.
So you've got more time?
More time for what?
Take that Tamagotchi, for example. That thing gives you a purpose.
That's why you love it. It needs you.
Okay. So imagine I gave you an agent that played it for you. The agent feeds it, cleans it, keeps it alive. 24-7. You'd never touch it again.
Look, creatives don't want an agent to make something for them. The whole point is making people feel emotional about our work.
And now we're handing that to a machine that's never felt a thing. Good ideas come from the mind, not a machine. Exactly.
AI can be used to help tell your story, but not automate the whole thing. The thing comes from within.
Anyway, I don't want more time. I just want something to do with it.
So the script for this one was relatively simple beyond that point.
It was just me describing each of those things that I wanted to convey that message through the Tamagotchi.
If you played the Tamagotchi and someone else was playing it for you, it would no longer become fun.
So I just found an analogy or a metaphor that I could use to tell the story.
And it helps users or people who are watching the video understand it through a lens that they can relate to.
And so that's why I chose to do it through a Tamagotchi.
And honestly, I just uh this.
So you can go through screenshot my scripts and just like really like process how I go through all of this.
But I just write in like cuts back to me, I roll my eyes, I fall backwards onto the grass, it cuts to a close-up shot of my face looking down at me.
And you can imagine as each of these things happen, that exact shot happens in C Dance.
So by being descriptive, you get the exact performance that you want.
The only thing that I would mention in here is make sure that you add in those nuances, those human acting performances that really elevate your work.
Now let's look at the actual generation process.
So here is what my first prompt looked like.
So you can see in here, I've got a reference of my character sheet right here.
So I designed my character. I even had Crocs on that says AI agents, which I thought was a fun little Easter egg.
And inside here, I have not only my character for myself, but I have my character sheet of what my character or my friend, Australian friend, looks like.
And I've also got references the location here, which was designed in mid journey.
And then I also have a reference of this prop here.
And this was the Tamagotchi.
But I was running into a lot of issues with copyright when I tried to use a Tamagotchi.
So I actually had to design a physical character sheet that labeled it as a PixelPal instead of labeling it as a Tamagotchi.
Because just by doing so, it wasn't allowing it to go through in C Dance 2.5.
So by labeling it and calling it something else, it just somehow got through the cracks.
But hey-ho, that's how it works.
Now my actual character sheets look like this.
The prompts to create them like so.
So I always use GPT image 2 to create my character sheets.
And I recommend that you do the same.
It is the most photorealistic model for designing character sheets.
So we use a reference image of me here or a specific existing character sheet of me.
And you can take a screenshot of this as a reference if you also want to use this character sheet like as a reference.
Take a screenshot of this and then just use a reference image of your face to create your own version of you as a character sheet.
And that's exactly what I did for this guy here.
So for this guy, I designed this character sheet before.
Again, and I used GPT image 2 for that. And don't feel free to take screenshots of any of these, by the way.
And then I liked this character here, and I also liked like his t-shirt.
I wanted to give him like more of like a graphic t-shirt and so we just kind of like I basically said like use this character sheet here as a reference.
I then just said add a summary graphic t-shirt onto this character here.
And then we got everything the same, but he's added a t-shirt onto him.
So that was my reference for the character.
So once I had one that I liked, I think I used this one for the actual project.
I also then had a reference of me in specific clothing that I liked, but I wanted to be wearing Crocs, so I eventually got to this one right here.
So I downloaded this one, and you can see my prompts right here for that as well. If you wanted to just copy it, feel free.
But that just shows you how we actually made our character sheets.
So once we have those ingredients, you can then very, very easily just upload them into your video generation platform of choice.
We are using Artcraft.
Reason we're using Artcraft is because there are less restrictions than other models, than like Higgsfield, Magnific, and other platforms like that.
So Artcraft, the C Dance version is the Chinese version and it's not the rest of the world version.
The Chinese version has less restrictions on copyright, so it's much easier to use to avoid any copyright issues or any bounce backs from any images being saying that your
restriction, content restriction, et cetera, This is where you can kind of get away with a lot more, and it's just a faster way for us to create.
So we use this platform to help us create videos which would not be possible on platforms like Higgsfield, Magnific, etc.
So you can see in here we've got our character sheets as references, we've also got my location reference, and I also designed our prop sheet for the Tamagotchi
in here.
And you can see I designed a couple of different versions of that right here.
So to create this, I uploaded my my actual character sheet in here.
I then uploaded a reference image of the product, which is just this right here, and I said create a product sheet for this product, right?
With just a reference of the character sheet as well.
And it gave us this.
But because it had the text of Tamagotchi on it, I actually had to remove it in Photoshop in order to get it to work.
So it didn't work. So there we go. I removed the Tamagotchi at the top here, but then it was also adding in text at the top that says Tamagotchi.
So you can see on the reference product here, I removed the word Tamagotchi up here, and I actually still was getting like text up here that said Tamagotchi on it, so it was getting restricted.
Then I said, don't mention the word Tamagotchi, and it called it pixel pal, and then this slipped through the cracks.
So that's just something that you can use. If you are struggling to use a certain reference, you just have to come up with creative ways to get around it.
And honestly, it works like a dream.
Like uh, you just need to be creative with the ways in which you try to get around the model restrictions.
So that's how we got our prop sheet.
Now you can see with all four of those ingredients uploaded, I then had my C dance prompt, which looks like this.
Now, obviously, I didn't type this, we used Claude to create it, but how did we do that?
Well, here is our entire conversation with Claude.
So this is exactly what I did to get my first C dance prompt off and running.
So what I did was I uploaded into Claude my references of my myself, my character, and the location here.
And I also uploaded a reference of a cinematic shot that I really liked, but I didn't actually end up using
this. And what I did was I just pasted in my entire script that I had made from this Google Doc, and I had just said inside Claude, I said,
now create a CDance 2.5 prompt with this.
And I literally pasted in my entire script in here.
I said you have 10,000 characters to get as descriptive as you can with the acting performances and nuances.
And then it wrote me out a script or a prompt, sorry, that was 9,963 characters because the maximum is 10,000 with C dance.
So I then got my whole prompt here, and all I did was to test it, was I copied it, I went into Artcraft, and I pasted it in here.
And this generation that you're about to watch right now was the first output that I got.
And there's a lot to learn in here.
So look at this.
Agents can do his entire job now. Nobody needs to work.
What's the fucking point?
Of what?
AI agents!
Why the fuck are we even building them?
They do your job for you, bro.
So you've got more time.
Okay. Creatives don't want an agent to make the play it for us.
The whole job is making gives you a job. The agent feeds it, cleans it, meeking keeps it alive 24.
So you can see the whole script's gone haywire.
Now why is that?
It's because it turns out that this entire video is gonna take longer than 30 seconds.
It's gonna take like a whole minute to get this entire script into a short 30-second sequence.
So what does that tell me?
Well, I'm glad you asked.
It tells me that now what I have to do is take this whole script and I said, maybe separate these out into two 30-second long prompts,
if it's going to be a minute long.
So then, naturally, it splits the whole project in two and it then writes 10,000 long characters for each of those two sections.
So we've got the same level of description and detail into those two scenes, but it's now separated out into two generations.
So I copy the first one, we go back into Artcraft, and then I get my second prompt.
My AI agents can do your entire job. I don't even need to work anymore.
What's the point?
Of what?
AI agents!
Like, why the fuck are we even building them?
They do your job for you, bro.
So you've got more time?
More time for what?
Take your Tamakochi.
That thing gives you a job.
That's why you love it. It needs you.
Something that's also really important to know to make sure that you get the right seedance prompt is you want to make sure that you have our custom seedance
skill that we've created for Claude installed inside of your Claude.
In order to do that, you want to make sure that when you are on Claude, you go to customize in here, you want to go to skills.
And I have a specific skill called the Video Prompt Builder.
And we'll make sure that we leave a link to this underneath this video for you so that you can go and install that into your own Claude so you can start getting all the right prompts.
And if I click on this, you'll see that it is an entire instruction list that takes your prompts and it formats it in the exact same way that our prompts come out.
And it also has all of the best cinematic verbiage, tone, everything is all written in there to make your prompts come out as crisp as possible.
So make sure that you download that and get that installed inside your Claude.
Now, how does the rest of this project come together? I've shown you that 30-second snippet.
Now, what I would do with that 30-second snippet that actually ended up turning out some parts of it were very usable.
So if we just scrub through this, some of the acting performance in here is not so great, for example, but some of it is pretty good.
And what we then do is we kind of look at all the generations that come through.
So this is really nice framing here. I love the acting performance, the biting of the lip, the eyebrow, the nuances, the the cut here to throw the phone, everything here is good.
However, you see here Take your Tamakochi. Right?
What's the fucking point?
So you see this part here where the character looks up and then looks at me.
There's this really long pause in here.
Right?
Until he does like any acting performance.
And so what we would do in our actual like final project, you'll see in here uh
I actually cut all of that out.
And so what I did was I just used the clip of him saying of what?
Of what, right? Which is this part here.
Of what.
Right?
I only use the key part of the video that helps move the story forward.
So I like to call this mining.
And this is where you mine out the best part of the video to use in your final cut.
So mining is a really key part, and that's where we mine out the good bits.
Of what?
Right? And then all of the acting that we have here.
AI agents!
AI agents, right? All of this acting.
What's really good about doing 30-second-long C dance generations is that the positioning of your characters and the continuity and flow between your shots
ends up being really, really high.
So you want to have that to make sure that you have consistency throughout your generations.
And this is what when you when you start to do individual clips and you do six seconds here, new generation six seconds here,
you'll notice the positioning of your characters moves ever so slightly between the clips because it doesn't have that context of that previous generation that you just did.
But when you do a 30-second long generation, the characters stay in the same spot, the acting performance between the cut is the exact same.
So here, for example.
Why the fuck are we even building them? They do your job Right?
So I finish in this position with my head tilted and I say, Why the F are we even building them?
And then when it cuts, my head is in the right position.
This character's in the right position.
Everything flows and the continuity is fantastic.
Or you bro, so you've got more time?
Right?
Now here, um, this part of my generation, I couldn't use.
Look at this.
I fall backwards, but I'm already off the bench.
So the continuity wasn't quite right just there.
So what I then had to do was I then would go back into Claude in this conversation, and you'll see I then said, okay, look, this isn't quite right.
So then I go back and I give it all of the detail of what I want to change.
So I've gone through and I've looked and I've observed at this generation, and I'm basically gonna go through Claude and I'm gonna say every single thing that I don't like about the video.
So this is exactly what I did.
I start play, I hit mute on the video, and I then start up my WhisperFlow.
Boom.
Now when I'm talking, Whisperflow is listening, and I then watch the video and I say, okay, between two seconds, when two seconds start,
I want to bite my lip earlier on in the scene and I want to raise my left eyebrow slightly earlier.
I also then want it to cut to a wide angle shot of me here, not a close-up shot at five seconds where I throw my phone on the floor.
I want it to be a wide shot.
Then at seven seconds, I want the character to look at me and be chuckling as soon as we cut to this character of this guy right here.
I want him to be chuckling straight away.
And then he kind of says immediately, for what?
So that way, continuity, there's not like this awkward silence and pause in there. And then I actually don't like the acting performance here.
I want to fold my legs because I think that my legs are just like, they're kind of just very stationary and static. I want there to be more acting nuances in there.
So I might fold my legs there, please.
Now we would paste that back inside inside Claude.
So you can see here, I would just remove this and I'd say, at two seconds, I want to bite my lip.
So now we're going back to Claude and we're iterating on the last prompt that we just had.
And we're gonna keep going through that process until we get the perfect generation that we're happy with.
So you can see here, I went through all that feedback.
Claude takes it on board, gives us a new prompt.
I copy that prompt, I go back into Artcraft, and I keep pasting it in until I get something that I'm happy with.
My AI agents can do your entire job.
I don't even need to work anymore.
What's the fucking point?
Of what?
AI agents!
Like, why the fuck are we even building them?
They do your job for you, bro.
So you've got more time.
Right, so some of the acting performance in here is good, but some of it I didn't like.
But what's important here is I realized in that faulty generation before where I fall off the side of the bench and it was like this malfunctioned part of the clip.
I then instructed it that I actually needed the character to fall forwards off the bench.
So now
I can take this part of the 30-second clip, right?
And then I can take different part and I can stitch everything together.
So now my sequence looks like this.
What's the fucking point?
Of what? AI agents! Like why the fuck are we even building them?
Okay, and when I we get to the point where I fall off the bench coming up. Do your job for you, bro, so you've got more time.
Here, I take that clip.
Perfect.
Then I cut to a totally different generation where I had this clip.
More time for
what?
Because I loved the cinematic quality of this clip. It was beautiful. The lighting, everything.
Composition, gorgeous.
The detail on the eyes, everything was just great.
So now I am stitching the best parts of all my generations together.
Because it's expensive. C Dance is expensive. We don't just want to let clips go to waste.
So I'm gonna take the best parts.
Now here's a really cool tip for you as well during the post-production process.
So let's say you have your clip, right? And this is your entire 30-second clip right here.
Now what you can do is inside Premiere Pro, you can right-click on your clip and you can scroll all the way down to scene edit
detection. And when you click on this, click on create clip marker at each detected cut point.
Click analyze.
And now look what happens.
It actually cuts each of your clips for you at the exact moment where the camera change is seen.
So you can see here, it will make those exact cuts for you so you can mine out those specific parts that you want in your video.
So you can take just the best bits, which is a really helpful speedy tip that you can use.
So that's in there.
Now we've got the first half of our video down.
Now it's about generating the second half of our video.
and this is where we deliver the second part of the story.
And so for that, we go back into Claude and we are basically just going to give more feedback.
So with the if you remember earlier, I said, let's take this video and cut it into two 30-second long pieces.
So here I have my part two, 28 seconds to one minute.
I copied this, we go into Artcraft, and I paste it in, okay?
And here is what I got for the first generation.
So imagine I gave you an agent that played it for you.
The agent feeds it, cleans it, keeps it alive. 24-7, you'd never touch it again.
Would you still love it?
You see that?
So, like, there's some really good parts in here.
I know.
Creatives don't want an agent to make something for them. The whole point is making people feel something emotional. And now we're handing that to a machine that's never felt a thing.
Here's something about C Dance. If you see your character speed of the audio picking up too quickly, it's because it's trying to get too much dialogue in in a very short space and period of time.
So that indicates that we actually need to make this even more than one just like one 30 second prompt. We might need to do a 30 second prompt plus an extra 10 seconds at the end.
But there's still really good bits that we can mine in here.
And also, this like cinematography in here is so beautiful.
It's really crisp.
You'll love it.
Okay, also when it comes to writing your video prompts, inside of Claude, we want to make sure that you have this kind of locked in at the start of your video.
And this global look is really, really key because this is what gives you that cinematic look throughout all of your video generations.
And you remember earlier I mentioned this right here.
And this is where this comes in clutch because you can download this image, for example, and we can go into Claude.
And when you go to start your generations, what you can do in your initial like images, when you give it all of these images plus your script,
you can actually upload as well this reference.
And you can say, like, I want you to use the same camera lens, same camera body for each of these video prompts to get the same look as the reference image that I've uploaded.
And then Claude will understand this image and it will then use that verbiage to lock in this part at the start of every single prompt.
35 millimeter using the ARRI cam.
It's gonna lock in all of that presets that you need for the lenses, the body, and everything to make sure all your shots remain consistent.
So this process is just an iterative one.
You simply break it down into 30-second chunks and then you provide feedback over and over and over until you get the results that you want.
And it's just going back and forth.
Okay, so here's another example of me kind of going back and describing changes that I want.
Look, creatives don't want an agent to make something for them.
Okay, so this wasn't what I wanted.
I want to see my face when I'm delivering these lines.
So I'm not happy with this generation.
Like I then went back to Claude and I described the nuances and things that I want to change, and then I got a generation like this, for example.
So imagine I gave you an agent that played it for you.
The agent feeds it, cleans it, keeps it alive 24-7. You'd never touch it again.
Would you still love it?
I don't know, man.
See?
So that's like that's a lot nicer.
And then we can just keep going and keep building.
And then I actually ended up with a really nice generation, and I realized that I needed a third generation in here.
So this was my third generation that I got.
Look, creatives don't want an agent to make something for them.
The whole point is making people feel emotional about our work.
So I actually took this section of this video and used it in the final project.
But the bit before that, I didn't like it. It wasn't good enough.
So I had to go over and over and over and continue to try and get the exact result that I wanted, and I got something like this, which was really nice.
Look, creatives don't want an agent to make something for them.
Right?
So I took that exact part from the video.
And you can see this is a whole 30-second-long generation.
But I just took this exact part of this video because I love the acting performance in it.
The whole point is making people feel emotional about our work.
And now you might be asking at this point, how are we getting my voice to come into the C dance here?
And you can see here the last ingredient that I've got in each of my shots is this black video right here.
Now, this is a nice little tip, and this is how I actually get the same voice in every single generation.
So what I did was I used my microphone and I recorded myself delivering this exact sentence.
Now listen here.
That quick beige fox jumped in the air over each thin dog.
Look out, I shout, for he's foiled you again.
Now you might be thinking, well, Rourke, why on earth are you saying a sentence like that?
And it's because it frenetically pronounces every single word in the English alphabet.
So what you can do is look up a sentence.
So a sentence that uses everything in the alphabet, right? Or every frenetic sound in the alphabet.
So a sentence that uses every frenetic.
Phrase.
And you can see here it is the quick beige fox jumped in the air over each thin dog. Look out, I shout, as he foiled you again, creating chaos.
So I read this and used that as my audio reference inside of Artcraft.
And by doing so, it then was able to take that as an audio sample and replicate that across each of my generations.
And all I had to do was simply say, okay, you can see inside my prompt here it says use at video one
as reference of man A.
And man A is me here in this example.
And so C Dance, we've actually used Claude to add that into our prompt.
So we've also said upload that audio sample into Claude. And we actually like to do it as a black MP4 video.
So you actually upload it as a video reference in here.
You'll see it's a video, not an MP3, right?
And so how do we do that?
Inside of our editing software of choice, we'll just go in here and then we will record our audio and then place it in and we'll just export it.
So for example, here we will just export our audio, any visuals in here, and we'll just export it.
And then we'll use that as our audio sample and we'll upload that as the reference inside of whatever tool or platform we're using to use C Dance.
So that is how we lock in a voice.
That is how we lock in our location, the props, the references of our characters, the cinematic style, the look.
Everything is locked in before we generate.
That way we know that everything is going to look the same.
The same camera, the same lens, everything feels consistent.
Then a lot of it is gambling at that point, to be honest, because you'll see here the locations of our positions of our characters here
have swapped from the original.
In my first generation, right, you can see here
I am sat on the left side of the bench and the Australian guy is on the right.
And so now it's up to me to make sure that my Australian guy is on the right side of the bench and I am on the left.
And in order to do that, you just have to either specifically ask for it so that the positions are in the correct way, and that way you have continuity between your shots,
or you just got to get a little lucky when you're generating.
And honestly, it's just about like you'll see here, I do a lot of the same prompt, and you can see all the only thing I'm adjusting is the acting performance,
right?
I'm testing to see whether this would look good or if this would look good, and I'm just testing to see what or or even this.
I tested for this too.
What would look the best? And I ended up just trying to find the best acting performance for that specific shot, and I settled on the best one, downloaded that, and put it all together in my project.
Now, once you have all your generations for the project, it's about putting that together in your post-production tool of choice.
And for me, this is Premiere Pro. I love editing in Premiere Pro. I think it's very easy, very fast, very efficient, industry standard.
So let's have a look at kind of what we did to put this all together.
So all we did here was add in some simple cuts where we've got this first generation in here.
And the original of this was actually much longer, but I shortened it because for social media, it's important that we get into the action nice and early.
We want to give an audience something to look at visually and also something to listen to at the same time as well.
So here I've got this nice opening frame, and I've also got the audio, which actually in the original started much later. So this is actually how the video should be played.
My AI agents can do your entire job.
Right?
That is what it first originally sounded like, but I just shifted the audio to play at the very beginning and overlaid it on top of our opening clip.
My AI agents can do your entire job. I don't even need to work anymore.
Right?
And then I cut it so that we throw the phone just after we finish hearing that.
What's the fucking point?
Of what?
Right? And then we're cutting to make sure that we're not adding in dead space.
We're removing any dead space of where the actors aren't delivering any good acting performance or any silences in there. Of what? AI agents!
Like why the fuck are we even And then it's all about sound design.
So we got really lucky with this generation in here, right? Where in here, you see the camera zoom in. Right here.
So all I had to do was add in a sound effect. Right?
To add that in there.
And then when it plays all together.
Like, why the fuck are we even building them?
Okay, and you'll see here.
Uh, if I extend out this clip, you'll see that it's actually they do your job for you, bro. So you've got more time.
And you can see in here we take an this is actually a clip from a totally different generation.
more time for what. Now, what's really nice about this shot is all these details under here.
It's all of the nuances of like the the hair not being totally perfect.
What?
Right?
I love this composition of this shot.
And and what you'll notice in these generations, we're only like 10, 12 seconds into this video. I've already used three different audio tracks.
I've used three different songs in the first 15 seconds.
Let's go back and listen.
My AI agents can do your entire job. I don't even need to work anymore. So we use a riser sound effect in there, and I also used one piano sound effect.
What's the fucking point?
Of what?
Next song. AI agents! Like, why the fuck are we even building them? They do your job for you, bro, so you've got more time.
Okay, and I faded that song out so that we then can we can have impact at this moment and then go to a new song.
More time for what?
So we've got three audio tracks in there.
Take that Tamagotchi, for example. That thing gives you a purpose. That's why you love it. It needs you.
Okay.
Then we've got our next song coming in here.
So imagine I gave you an agent that played it for you. The agent feeds it, cleans it. That's our fourth song.
Keeps it alive, 24-7. You'd never touch it again. Look, creatives don't want an agent to make something for them. The whole point is making people feel emotional about our work.
And now we're handing that to a machine that's never felt a thing. Good ideas.
And then I also have a another music track right at the end.
But one thing that I think is important to know is that on these clips, I would always recommend that you add lumetry color design.
So for those of you who don't know, lumetri color is just what enables you to add small changes to your video.
So whether that be temperature, right, you can adjust the temperature of your video.
Whether that be saturation of your video, if you want to like increase the saturation a little bit, or the exposure, which just ups the brightness a little bit
too.
So if, for example, I take a clip like this one, right?
And I added a lumetry colour effect onto this clip, you can adjust the let's say the saturation, make it a little
more saturated, the exposure ever so slightly.
Now, if you take a look at this clip before and after, here is before, after, before, after, it just makes it pop a little bit more.
And then when you sh when you see it on your mobile phone, it helps significantly.
So just giving it a little bit of pop is also really, really nice.
And you can use DaVinci Resolve if you want to go into real detail of color grading.
But I just like for me on my projects, a final touch that I do is saturation and exposure.
I just adjust them ever so slightly just to make it pop that little bit more.
And whatever I do on one clip, I need to make sure that I apply that onto every other clip so it's continual across all of our scenes because we don't want them to look different.
One of the last touches is also just adding in simple captions, and that's very simple in itself.
Just adding captions inside whatever editing tool as well.
For social media purposes, it means people who are listening and watching your video without audio on can enjoy the visual production that you've put together.
So for me, when we're creating a cinematic piece, it's all of these steps.
Now, where would I recommend that you do your sound design?
It would be Artlist.
In here, they have really great sound effects that you can use. You can search for anything. So let's say riser, you can find really great riser sound effects in here.
Right?
Anything that you could possibly dream of, they've got it on this platform.
They also have some AI video generation stuff in here, which is fine.
The real reason I like to use it is for their music and also the sound effects.
Now, if you are generating some of your own music, sometimes I do like to use Suno.
Suno is really, really good for making your own custom music projects.
So, for example, if we go in here, I'll show you some of my ones.
So in here, you can hear this.
Right, all of these are custom tracks that I've built for specific cinematic pieces.
and you can just describe what you want with Claude.
and you can just say on a new chat, "I'd like a a song for like a video that I'm making, and it's on like how AI agents,
I don't like them, and they're there, but it's like a cinematic piece.
So I want there to be like pianos. I want it to be quite slow.
The general like tempo and script of the the video is this.
And then what you can do is you can actually paste in your Claude. So if we go back into Claude here, you can paste in your prompts that you've got.
So, or you could just take it from Artcraft.
So, for example, if you go in here, AI agents because Claude understands the time codes of all of the prompts that we've got,
so you can see in here zero to two seconds, two to five seconds, it understands the pacing and the tempo.
So then do is it can go and write a prompt for us that will match the tempo of our prompt.
So it can actually be custom built, and the key moments and impact moments can happen at the exact moments that we want them to happen in our project.
So you see how everything starts to come together.
But Claude is really our central place that we're using to actually build everything that we need.
So here we go. We've got slow piano, 62 beats per minute, C minor.
So it can we can copy this, and you see here it lives as a Suno prompt.
So we can copy that, we can go into Suno and just paste it in here. And it's actually very quick to create this music.
This model or Suno is incredibly fast at creating music tracks.
And this is a really, really nice way. If you can't find stock music that fit the project that you need, you can just make your own.
It's that fast and it's already finished.
And listen to this, it's beautiful.
So we have custom tracks that we can make, we can use sound effects from Artlist to bring everything together, and then you can edit it all in your you know
software of choice.
And honestly, this is the process that we go through for every single cinematic project that we've done.
So, for example, we did this video here, which went formed really, really well, which was a cinematic piece that we did, which was a parody of Harry Potter.
And we had a lot of fun with it, and we broke down each of like the four houses of Harry Potter into the different AI large language models, like
Claude, Gemini, Grok.
We had a lot of fun with this project, and we created some really cinematic shots, and you can see those inside our Artcraft right here.
So if we go in here and have a look at our video, so here you can see some of our generations coming in.
And honestly, you'll see, especially now that all of these are playing, you'll see that there's very subtle changes from each of these videos,
whether that's wind blowing or no wind blowing, or whether or not we wanted fog to be kind of blowing across my feet at the start of the video or not.
All of these are subtle nuances that we wanted to change in each of the videos.
And then honestly, it was just a process of constantly refining, writing out the script, giving it all the detail, giving that script to
reclaude, and you can see we've got that locked-in camera style at the start of our videos, and then you can see all of our ingredients in here.
So we've got our character references, we've got our object references, and we'll use mid-journey or GPT-2
to create these references.
We've also got other characters who are going to show up inside these scenes.
But then interestingly, we have designed these locations like so.
These are designed with mid-journey, and we've also got still frame references like this as well, for example.
And now we get an output like this.
Wait till you get the sloppards.
You've got no idea how many credits you'll be spending.
You really don't feel like listening to me today, eh? What's the road, pussy?
What are those symbols?
Wait, right?
So we just break it down into small parts and we take the best bits of each one.
And you can see here for us, it takes us a lot of generations to get the exact thing that we're looking for. And it takes time, but eventually you get there.
And when you stitch everything together, you get something that you're truly like very happy with and proud of.
So all of the ideation shot deck comes from color grading.
We get mid journey to design our locations, and then we eventually get something that we're super, super proud of.
And lastly, again, you can see here we're using this audio, which is me talking over each thin dog.
Look how I shout for to use Inside C Dance to get my voice as the exact voice that we want for all of our video generations.
And once again, the exact same process for this one right here.
The color grade was found on Shot Deck.
We then started to create our own locations, and this one was actually slightly more different. I actually really enjoyed the process of this one.
So this, for example, was a reference photo that I took in real life.
And you can see here, this is the actual photo that I took, and I wanted to color grade it into the cinematic style that I wanted for this project.
And I used Claude to do that.
I upload this image into Claude and I then uploaded a reference that I found from Shop Deck, and I said,
I want to change my original reference image to match the cinematic color grading of this reference that I found in Shop Deck.
Can you give me a prompt that will adjust it with Nano Banana Pro?
And then it gave me this prompt here: keep the composition, the framing, the geometry, the architecture, everything the same, but just adjust it so that it has the 35 millimeter
grain, all of the same detailed about the cinematic style, and it adjusted each of my images to match.
So here is another reference right here.
So here is my original, and then I have my color graded scene.
So we're using AI to attach the color grading from cinematic shots into our scenes, and those can then be used as references,
which you can see right here. So here is my original, and here is the color graded version.
And so we're just using the same prompt and we're then just adjusting all of the color grading onto this image.
And I use those as references to create this whole project, and then we get that look in all of our scenes.
So this is really, really effective.
So now you can create cinematic content with AI that actually gets results.
And if you want to learn more about becoming a creative AI professional, then you can come and join GenHQ.
We've already generated over a million dollars for our students so far, and we've created nearly 500 jobs for creatives.
So if you're interested in turning AI into your full time career, then you can click the first link in the description to come and join us at GenHQ.